The war is eternal. His mission is just the beginning.
Priest is a action, fantasy, horror film directed by Scott Stewart.
In an alternate world, humanity and vampires have warred for centuries.
After the last Vampire War, the veteran Warrior Priest lives in obscurity
with other humans inside one of the Church's walled cities.
When the Priest's niece is kidnapped by vampires, the
Priest breaks his vows to hunt them down.
He is accompanied by the niece's boyfriend, who is a
wasteland sheriff, and a former Warrior Priestess.
Priest, played by Paul Bettany.
Black Hat, played by Karl Urban.
Lucy Pace, played by Lily Collins.
Priestess, played by Maggie Q.
Owen Pace, played by Stephen Moyer.
Hicks, played by Cam Gigandet.
Priest is a 2011 American action horror film directed by Scott Stewart, written by
Cory Goodman, and starring Paul Bettany as the title character.
It is loosely based on the Korean comic of the same name by Hyung Min-woo, in
turn inspired by the computer game Blood by Monolith Productions.
Set in an alternate universe where humanity and vampires have warred for centuries, after the last Vampire War, a
veteran Warrior Priest lives in obscurity until his niece (Lily Collins) is kidnapped by vampires.
The film was released on May 13, 2011.
The film earned over $78 million at the box office against a $60 million production budget, but it was panned by critics, who praised the film's
visual style and art direction while criticizing the movie's use of genre clichés, writing, acting, editing, and action scenes.
The film explores themes of vampire, dystopia, post-apocalyptic
future, crucifixion, vampire hunter (slayer).
The tone is dark and intense.